## XIAOYU CHEN / MAVIS

Phone: (61)- 0450-520-805 E-mail: <a href="mailto:mavischen916@gmail.com">mavischen916@gmail.com</a>
GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/xychenxy">https://github.com/xychenxy</a> Website: <a href="https://mavis-developer.netlify.app">https://github.com/xychenxy</a> Website: <a href="https://mavis-developer.netlify.app">https://mavis-developer.netlify.app</a>

## **ABOUT ME**

I have been working in the Australia ICT environment for more than two years and gained commercial experience. I primarily focus on JavaScript/ES6, HTML5 and CSS3, and I develop websites/desktop app with a number of frameworks such as React, Node.js, Electron and WordPress. I have experience on integrating API, such as UBER API, Australia Post API and Shopify StoreFront API.

## **KEY SKILLS**

- Front-end: React.js/Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS3, Sass/Less, Bootstrap, Ant Design, Material-UI, Electron (Desktop apps), WordPress, Gatsby/React, GraphQL, Webpack
- Back-end: Node.js/Express, NPM, Yarn, Java, Python, PHP/WordPress/Symfony
- Database: NoSQL/MongoDB, MySQL
- API: Uber API, Shopify StoreFront API, Couriers Please API, Google API, JSON, RESTful API, Axios, Postman
- Testing: Jest, Mocha
- Cloud: AWS EC2, Route53, CloudFront, S3, Nginx, CI/CD
- Version Control: Git, GitHub, Bitbucket
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum

#### **WORK HISTORY**

### Full-stack developer

8/2020 - 5/2021

Palette, Melbourne, Australia

https://tintpaint.com/

- Using React/Redux, Node.js, Electron.js, TypeScript, Ant-Design, MongoDB, AWS, Bitbucket, Nginx, PM2, Figma.
- I am responsible for two main projects alone, warehouse system and Analytics dashboard.
- Developing and maintaining Tint Mix, manufacturing automation system for processing eCommerce orders, tinting paint, tracking stock levels, integrating with dispatch partners, generating daily reports with auto-email function, and tracking user analytics and dispatch partner performance.
- Integrating Uber API, Australia Post API, Shopify StoreFront API, Couriers Please API and Dear Inventory System.
- Optimizing existing user interface design of desktop app (warehouse system).
- Caching database queries and API responses for better performance.
- MongoDB migration.
- Deploying in AWS EC2 with Nginx and PM2 tools.

### Front-end developer

12/2020 - 1/2021

Foodifox, Melbourne, Australia

https://foodifox.com/

- Using Gatsby/React/GraghQL, HTML, CSS3, Adobe XD, Netlify, GoDaddy and GitHub.
- Single handling the whole website, including developing five pages and deployment.

Web developer

7/2019 - 1/2020

RMIT University and Opening the Door Foundation

https://app.openingthedoors.org.au/

- Using Symfony/PHP, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, AWS
- Assessing project requirements using Agile & Scrum principles
- Creating all web pages with Bootstrap framework
- Assisting teammates to writing and executing test cases
- As a casual web developer at RMIT to maintain the project discussed above
- Integrating SendGrid API and fixing SSL issue

Full-stack developer

1/2019 - 4/2019

AIU Group, Melbourne, Australia

https://www.aiugroup.com.au/

- Using WordPress/PHP, Bootstrap, MySQL, AWS
- Single handling the whole website, including developing ten pages and deployment.

#### Software testing engineer

12/2010 - 2/2016

Tokheim Technology Co., Ltd., Guangzhou, China

- Designing and Executing 2000 test cases for Fuel POS and Fuel Dispensers
- Developing automatic testing tools for fuel encoder to save up 80% time
- Participating in the Internal and External Audit of IOS90001

## **EDUCATION**

#### RMIT University, Melbourne, Australia

3/2018-12/2019

- Major: Master of Information Technology
- WAM: 76/100

# Beijing Institute of Technology | Zhuhai, China

9/2007 - 7/2011

- Bachelor of Traffic Engineering
- WAM: 80/100